Leah: Let’s now look at Kanban
starting with its strengths
Chris: Easy to learn and use -Kanban
is very straightforward with its
approach and is easy to learn and use.
It can be used in small simple projects
such as for children to help plan
their homework; to complex business
projects using the Scrum framework.
Leah: Visual-It is a visual system,
and the flow of work is managed
using a Kanban project board.
In its simplest form there are
three columns which are labelled:
‘To Do’, ‘In Progress’, and ‘Done’.
Chris: Adaptable and flexible-It
is adaptable and flexible as
there can be no planned timings
and priorities and workload can
be changed during the project.
It is also flexible in that it can be
used with another framework such as Scrum.
Leah: Collaborative-As a simple visual
system, it helps the project team to
collaborate as it simplifies planning,
helps to manage work and inventory, and
increase productivity and efficiency.
Chris: Low overheads-It has low
overheads as there is no training
needed and all you need is a Kanban
project board to get started.
Leah: Reduces costs and waste-As
it can be used with LEAN’s
‘Just In Time’ methodology it
helps to reduce cost and waste.
Chris: And the Weaknesses
Needs another framework to work-Kanban
would need a framework such as
Scrum or LEAN ‘Just in Time’ to
work as it needs the supporting
elements that they would give.
Leah: Not suitable on plans that are
not stable-Kanban would need plans
that are stable and consistent to
work effectively, so this may be an
issue if the plans need to be dynamic.
Chris: Is not Iterative-Another framework
would be needed for iterations to be
used which would normally end up being
a separate project, as iteration is not
essential to Kanban at a ticket level.
Leah: Lack of timing-Because
Kanban is adaptable and flexible,
there are often no planned timings
for each stage of the project.
This also means that items can
be changed during the project,
and this could cause issues.
Chris: A Kanban project could be as
simple as cleaning your house or planning
school homework or college exams.
In the workplace examples could include
giving a project manager visibility
to a project status; using a Kanban
board to delegate work across a team;
or connecting related work items across
different projects or project boards.